(dramatic music)
(blasting)
(booming)
The continued wave of
death-dealing explosions
struck yesterday at area
defense headquarters
as in previous occasions
the authorities are unable
to detect the cause of these blasts
which have done untold damage.
Who could possibly be doing this?
Well there are several theories Joan,
but so far no one is even
sure what kind of explosives
are being used or how they're set off.
Maybe Mr. Henderson will
have some information
for us when he gets in from Washington.
That guy Henderson wouldn't
tell you what time it is.
Just what is his job anyway?
He won't tell you that
either Ted, it's a big one.
He only answers to a few
people in this country of ours.
I think that... (knocking)
Hello Mr. Henderson.
-Hello Commander Cody.
Ted, Miss Gilbert.
How are you getting along
with the rocket ship?
As well as can be expected sir.
Our test with the model is satisfactory.
If the government will
let us make a few test
flights with the rocket...
It's out of the question.
This whole project is strictly top-secret.
Since you people developed the rocket ship
for us and we'll be the ones operating it,
it has been decided that you
should know more of our plans.
I've been authorized to tell you this much:
its primary use will be to combat this wave
of sabotage and destruction
of our defense system.
You mean the government
knows what's causing it?
Not definitely, but tests
of the wreckage show that
the explosions are of atomic origin.
You mean someone's
dropping atomic bombs on us?
Not bombs; No planes have been observed,
and the explosions aren't severe enough.
No, from what I've learned of the nature of
the blast they see more like
an atomic ray of some kind.
Of course that's just a guess.
It's the same guess that we've made
because it's the only possible answer.
[Cody] But no one has ever been able to
make an atomic ray machine.
You mean no one on earth ever has.
Say, this rocket we're
building we'll be able
to fly to the moon, maybe someone up there's
built one that could get down here.
We believe that possible,
and for some time our
astronomers have been noticing
an unusual amount of atomic
activity on the moon.
Atomic activity on the moon.
Atomic blasts on the Earth.
The two known facts fit together.
Yes, it adds up.
So that's why you want
us to fly to the moon.
Yes, and when you get to the moon find out
if these attacks are
actually coming from there
and try to devise some
plan for stopping them.
In the meantime we'll do we
can with these attacks here.
Is your flying suit still working?
Yes.
We may ask you to use it.
If a ray gun is being used
to cause these blasts,
it's probably being operated from the ground
and if you could get to the scene of
the attack soon enough,
you might be able to find
some clue to the attackers.
I'll be glad to try.
Good, we'll phone you as soon as we
have any information about another attack.
All right, sir.
-Goodbye.
(light instrumental music)
(horn honking)
There she is, right on time.
(blasting) (dramatic music)
(chuckling)
Well, that did it.
Let's get over to Kern Pass.
That troop train will be along soon.
All right I'll get out there right away.
Say, give me a hand with
the flying suit, Ted.
Sure.
A trainload of army supplies was just
blasted off the west end of the valley.
A rancher reported he saw a truck parked on
a hill overlooking the
tracks with two men in it.
Working some kind of a gun.
They pulled out right after the wreck
and headed toward Kern Hills.
Henderson's office gave a
description of the trucks
and I'm going out to look for it.
I suppose you'll be wanting this.
Yes I may need it.
(light dramatic music)
(blasting)
She ought to be along anytime now.
(chugging)
Okay get set.
Now!
(banging)
Let's get out of here!
And leave the ray gun?
What else can we do?
The loss of the ray gun is not too serious.
I brought sufficient equipment from
the moon to build several of them
but I do not care to have
the Earth people learn
the secrets of our weapons.
From the description you gave me of
your attackers costume it must have
been Commando Cody in his flying suit.
He will probably take our ray gun to his
laboratory for examination
so you must go there at once and recover
the atomic chamber from the ray gun.
That's a large order Krog.
We hired out to work your
ray gun, this business...
You were hired to do anything
that I may consider necessary to pave
the way for our invasion from the moon.
You're being well paid for your work,
so do as you're ordered.
Okay.
(light dramatic music)
Is working on this gun going to hold
up finishing the rocket ship?
No, I'll just give it a quick examination
and then turn it over to the authorities.
We'll still be able to take off
for the moon next Wednesday.
Take it easy and you won't get hurt.
Move back.
There's the unit we want, grab it.
(dramatic music) (clattering)
(grunting)
(thudding)
(banging)
And don't try to follow us.
(light spooky music)
[Krog] Krog Calling Retik.
Krog calling Retik.
Come in, Krog.
A rocket ship is leaving here in five days
to investigate our moon.
I did not believe the earth men possessed
a ship capable of making the journey.
I just learned about it myself
but I'm sure my information is correct.
Very well, it is not too serious.
We will be prepared to take care of
the visitors when they arrive.
I still think this is no trip for a woman.
Now don't start that again,
you'll be very glad to have someone along
who can cook your meals.
I'll say we will.
Don't give her any more arguments.
Okay, I like to eat too.
Well boys that's it.
Well the best of luck to all of you sir.
Hope this thing works all right.
So do we.
See ya, bye.
-Goodbye, sir.
Hiya, folks.
Hello Hank.
All set?
All warmed up, we can take off right now,
that is if the ship will stand up to
the test we made with the model.
I think it will.
Now, let's go.
Safety belts fastened?
Fire pilot jets.
(air hissing) (light dramatic music)
Fire main jets!
(whirring)
Right, well you'd hardly
know we were moving.
Well, believe it or not we are.
A lot of miles per minute.
She's living up to the test we made.
Set a course for the moon.
Right.
Take over here, will ya, Ted?
(light suspenseful music)
We're just about here.
Looks like we're on the right track.
We ought to be down in another two hours.
(whirring)
There's a city just ahead.
[Hank] Where do we sit down?
Let's take her back in those hills where
we can find a place to hide the ship
and I'll fly over the city in the rocket suit.
Okay.
Settle down in that canyon.
(clattering)
(blasting) (light dramatic music)
You are going in the
right direction, Earth man.
Enter the first door you come to.
Turn the control, the door will open.
(creaking)
Welcome, Commando Cody.
I am Retik, ruler of the Moon.
Apparently you are expecting me.
Of course.
For many years our radio
has kept us informed
of events on Earth and my men there
have advised me of your every move.
I see you have adopted our language.
Yes, all our people are
required to speak English
so we can operate more
efficiently in your country.
You mind telling me why
your men are carrying out
that campaign of destruction on Earth?
Not at all.
They are merely softening up your defenses
for our impending invasion.
Why do you want to invade the earth?
Because the atmosphere
on the moon has become
so thin and dry it is impossible for us
to raise food except in
pressurized greenhouses
and none of us can move
outside without helmets
so we are planning a mass
migration to your world.
You will find that conquering
the earth isn't so simple.
Ah, but it will be because
of our atomic weapons
on the Moon we have an element, Lunarian,
which is far superior to uranium as a base
for atomic reactions and
we can completely control
the force of these reactions enabling us
to build atomic weapons
ranging from huge cannon
to these small ray pistols.
It's very considerate of you
to give me all this information.
You deserve some reward
for your long journey,
but unfortunately I cannot permit you
to return to Earth with it.
Maybe I have something to say about that.
(dramatic music)
(whirring)
So much for the
effectiveness of your weapons.
Now I will demonstrate one of ours.
(blasting)
(dramatic music)
Seize him!
(clattering)
(thudding)
(blasting)
(clattering)
(dramatic music)
(thudding) (blasting)
(clattering)
(booming)
(creaking)
(blasting) (light dramatic music)
(buzzing)
So Retik plans to invade the Earth
with his army from the Moon.
As soon as the saboteur's,
he already has their finish
softening up our defenses.
Do you think he'll be able to do it?
I'm afraid he might.
I don't know how many men
or rocket ships he has,
but his atomic weapons are
so far ahead of anything
we have he wouldn't need a very big army.
What did you find out about the ray guns?
Only that they use an
element called Lumarium.
Instead of uranium as the base
for their atomic reactions.
They apparently can control the reaction
so they will work either
as a disintegrating ray
or as an explosion like our atomic bomb.
Well if their weapons are that powerful
it would be impossible for
our people to attack them here
even if we had rockets
enough to transport an army.
That's right.
Apparently they let us land
because they weren't afraid
of a single ship but they
would undoubtedly blast
it at an invading fleet.
Then hadn't we better go back right
away and warn our people?
Our orders were to find out if the attacks
were coming from here and if so,
to try to figure out some way to stop them.
And those are large orders.
All we have is a light machine
gun and some hand grenades.
They wouldn't do much to that walled city.
No, but there was one of their ray guns
in Retik's laboratory.
If I could get hold of that it would be easy
to blast open their pressurized buildings
and really put them out of business.
All you've gotta do is get the gun.
That may not be too tough.
We brought some nitrous
oxide with us, didn't we?
Yes there's a small tank of it.
I'll find the air-intake that
leads to Retik's laboratory
and turn the gas into it, that
ought to put them to sleep
long enough to let me
get away with a ray gun.
If it's like the gun you found on Earth
it'll be too heavy to
carry, let alone fly with.
That's right, but the tripod isn't important.
I'll dismantle a gun from the tripod.
I think I can handle a gun all right.
Maybe you can but it'll be quite a load.
I better get a helmet and go with you.
Hank and Joan can stay
here and guard the ship.
Okay, I may need some help with that.
(light suspenseful music)
You better not come any closer.
I'll fly on in and get the gun.
I'll manage to lug it back this far myself.
[Ted] With the whole town chasing you?
[Cody] I don't think
they can get around outside
very well, but we'll find out.
(dramatic music)
(blasting)
Nesor, something's wrong
the ventilating system.
Get the oxygen.
(thudding)
(creaking)
(clanking)
(dramatic music)
(grunting)
(thudding)
(crashing)
(buzzing)
Guards, guards!
The Earth man has escaped with a ray gun,
send a car out to search for him.
(rumbling)
-You got it.
-Yeah.
But it sure is heavy.
-Is anybody after you?
-Not yet.
Give me a hand with this.
We've got to move fast.
(suspenseful instrumental music)
(rumbling)
[Guard] He must have come this way,
he couldn't have got by the
guards at the canyon bridge.
[Guard] No, and he won't move
very fast carrying that gun.
There they are, give them a blast.
(blasting)
[Ted] What do we do now?
[Cody] Let's try to keep going.
Maybe we could dodge around
those rocks and lose them.
[Ted] They're still after us, let's go.
[Cody] That looks like a
cave, let's get in there.
[Guard] We can't follow them in there.
Set the ray gun at constant heat,
it will melt the cliff and bury them alive.
Right. (Dramatic music)
[Ted] What's that?
[Cody] They turned the ray gun into the side
of the cave and it's melting the rock.
Let's get back as far as we can.
Never mind the gun!
(dramatic music)
[Guard] That will finish them.
(suspenseful music) (bubbling)
[Cody] Maybe we can get out along that side.
[Ted] But what about that tank?
[Cody] We may be able to take care of it.
(suspenseful music)
Let's try this one.
[Guard] That will finish them.
[Cody] Get me a hand grenade.
(booming)
[Guard] They must have gotten out,
let's move out of here.
(rumbling)
[Cody] That does it Ted,
let's get back to the rocket ship.
Too bad you lost that ray gun.
You'll have a tough time
getting another one now.
We haven't a chance of getting one,
and we couldn't possibly attack their city
with any of our weapons.
That isn't the worst of it.
They've already tracked us halfway to
this ship so they know about where we are.
It's only a question of
time until they find us.
One blast from that ray gun
will pop this ship like a toy balloon.
Maybe we better get back to earth.
I think so.
We've accomplished the most
important part of our mission;
we discovered that Retik is planning to lead
an invasion from the moon as soon as the
saboteurs finish softening up our defenses,
and it's up to us to get that
information back to Earth.
How soon can we take off?
Well I've gotta build
up the pressure in all the
tanks and warm up the
jets, maybe a couple hours.
Then get started.
I'll fly out and scout
around until you're ready.
(light suspenseful music)
(clicking)
Scout Seven reporting to headquarters.
Come in.
I found the earth man's
rocket ship, Your Excellency,
it's in a canyon only about a mile west
where our scout car was attacked.
Splendid.
I'll send another car out after it at once.
Stay there and keep watch.
[Scout] Yes, sir.
(blasting) (dramatic music)
(thudding)
(smacking)
(blasting)
The scout found our ship.
I took care of 'em but I'm
afraid he already reported us.
How much longer before we can take off?
[Ted] One of those tanks is headed this way!
How 'bout it, Hank?
I won't guarantee the
results but we can try.
Here it goes, all jets.
(hissing)
(light suspenseful music)
Looks like we may make it.
If we get out of range
of that ray gun in time.
(rumbling)
(booming)
Shut off that induction valve!
Protect the other compartments.
Right!
(blasting)
Well, that one barely reached us.
Looks like we're in the clear.
Things are sort of messed up
in there, but nothing serious.
Okay, Hank, you can start for the earth now.
Make a 180 degree turn.
Right, Commando.
Homeward bound.
Very well.
Patrol car reported that
the spaceship has escaped.
That ship must not be
allowed to land on Earth.
Retik to Krog.
(light music)
Come in, Retik.
Commano Cody's rocket ship has escaped
and is headed back to Earth.
He has all the information
about our planned invasion
and must not be allowed to
tell it to the authorities.
Will you have a ray gun
completed by the time he lands?
I'm afraid that is
impossible, Your Excellency.
[Retik] Then use of bomb
any other weapon available.
That ship must be destroyed before
anyone could get out of it.
Yes, Your Excellency.
You heard the orders.
Yeah but it might not be that easy.
There may be guards at the landing field.
Nevertheless you will
carry out instructions.
I will furnish you with a bomb,
you can devise some means for placing
it under the ship the moment it lands.
How do we know when they'll get here?
I'll pick up their approach on my radar
so you can be in position when they land.
(light music)
Just like we figured.
Yes, we've got to blast them, then plant
the bomb before anyone
can get out of a ship.
Here she comes.
(rumbling)
Going in for a landing.
Calling landing field.
Landing field to rocket, come in.
We're coming down.
Is the field clear?
Yes, sir we're all ready for you.
All right, Hank, make your 180 degree turn.
You take the one on the right.
(banging) (dramatic music)
Let's get over to the car!
We'll never make it
now, let's get outta here.
(rumbling)
They're taking off in a car.
I'm gonna go after them, you guard the ship!
(engine rumbling)
They're after us, step on it!
(tires screeching)
He's hanging onto us, give it all you can.
Stop on that bridge!
(tires screeching)
(frantic dramatic music)
(hissing)
(booming)
(dramatic music)
(tires screeching)
Stop on that bridge!
(light dramatic music)
(screeching)
(booming)
(splashing)
So the people on the Moon are planning
a direct attack on the world as soon as
their saboteurs have
softened up our defenses.
What do you think their
chances are of succeeding?
You've seen what the ray
guns have already done here.
If they send out a fleet
of rocket ships armed
with atomic weapons like those
or perhaps even larger ones
it would be difficult to
hold out against them.
Perhaps our best move would be
to attempt an attack on the Moon.
We'd be at a terrific disadvantage.
I don't even see how we could land ships
there in face of their ray guns.
But we just can't sit here
and wait to be attacked.
No, of course not.
Retik the Ruler told me
they plan to attack after
their saboteurs here have
accomplished their mission.
If we could round up the gang operating here
we may stave off the attack until
we are better prepared to meet it.
Yes that's certainly the first thing to do.
You know some of the saboteurs don't you?
Yes, well that is by sight.
And my flying suit gives
me a considerable advantage
in running them down.
Right.
I'll have you notified whenever
there's another attack.
In the meantime we'll put every
available man on this case.
Goodbye Cody.
-Goodbye sir.
(light dramatic music)
I'll have this ray gun
finished in a short time now
so you'd better arrange to get
another truck to mount it in.
Okay, but I'll need some more money.
You'll have to sell some
more of those jewels
you brought down from the moon.
I've only a few of them left
and I must keep those for an emergency.
It will be necessary for you to take
up your career of bank robbery.
Not me.
I'm already on parole for that.
I know but you would be wise
to continue to obey my orders.
Your more recent activities would be
of extreme interest to the authorities.
Will you need someone to help you?
Yeah, but they'll have to do the dirty work.
Of course I'll go along to check on them.
Very well, make your arrangements at once.
Select a bank which is located
in a not too heavily patrolled area.
(light dramatic music)
(alarm ringing)
Something went wrong.
Here they come.
(banging)
(engine rumbling)
After that car.
Step on it!
(banging)
We oughta lose 'em now,
we're out of traffic.
(crashing)
But we must have more money.
You've got to get it somehow.
Not by any more bank jobs.
I'm too hot in that business now.
We'll have to figure out something else.
I'll radio the moon,
perhaps Retik can advise us.
Krog calling Retik.
(light spooky music)
Come in, Krog.
I have to report that our scheme
for obtaining money was a
failure Your Excellency.
Can you suggest some plan
that might be more successful?
I think I can.
From what I hear of activities on Earth
kidnapping important persons and holding
them for ransom has
proved highly profitable.
Commando Cody who threw
his rocket ship to the moon
is very valuable to the defense
organization of his country.
I suggest you select him.
An excellent idea.
We shall carry it out at once.
It'll be a rough deal,
but a lot safer than robbing another bank.
Of course.
Commando Cody should be
worth at least $100,000.
Shall we bring him here?
No.
Hire a plane and take him to...
(light instrumental music)
(tapping)
Where's Cody?
[Ted] Right over there.
(dramatic music)
(thudding)
(clattering)
(grunting)
Now will you tell us where Cody is?
I don't know.
Why don't we grab her
and use her to trap Cody?
That's an idea.
On your way sister.
Wait a minute.
(light dramatic music)
What happened?
Those same two men who wrecked
the ray gun, they came after you.
Where's Joan?
I don't know, maybe they took her with them.
Two men and a woman drove away
from here just as I came in.
They were too far away to be recognized
but it must have been them.
Police headquarters.
(engines buzzing) (dramatic music)
(tires screeching)
Okay I'll tell him.
The police found out that
the car went to the Eastside.
Airport and a man took off
with Joan in a trotted plane.
They left just a few minutes ago.
If I'm lucky I can catch them.
(blasting) (dramatic music)
(engine rattling)
Don't get excited, sister.
I'll take care of him.
(banging)
(clicking)
(dramatic music)
He wrecked the controls.
(booming)
(dramatic music)
(engine rumbling)
He wrecked the controls.
[Cody] Get into that parachute.
(booming)
What became of that man?
[Cody] He must have
landed somewhere near here.
If you're sure you're all
right, I'll look for him.
Oh, of course I am I'll
walk over to the road.
[Cody] Okay.
(blasting) (dramatic music)
How about a ride to town mister?
Well sure, hop in.
(blasting)
Man in a flying suit chasing us, step on it.
Huh, are you crazy?
Don't argue, step on it.
(banging)
That stopped him.
You keep going.
(rustling)
I must report to the Moon.
Krog calling Retik.
Come in Krog.
I have to report another
failure, Your Excellency.
We were unable to capture Commando Cody
and hold him for ransom.
You still have no funds.
No, sir.
And until we can get a ray gun into action
again we are unable to continue our
campaign against Earth's defenses.
Listen carefully Krog,
I cannot have my preparations
for invading the earth
delayed by such a minor detail as
obtaining a small amount of money.
If the men you now have cannot accomplish
this simple mission then hire
someone who can produce results.
This is an order!
I understand, Your Excellency.
You heard.
It's up to you to decide
whether you can still
be useful to us or...
We'll figure something out.
Remember that payroll job Duke
was trying to get you in on?
Maybe he'll still go through with it.
Well?
It's risky but it might work.
It's the Western Wholesale Supply Company.
They keep their payroll in
the office safe every Friday night.
There's a man in the office
who knows the combination.
(alarm ringing)
(dramatic music)
(whistle blowing)
There's a cop, get going.
(banging)
Hold up men in a black sedan.
They took the turn to the right.
(dramatic music)
(tires screeching)
(banging)
They're gettin' closer.
We can't get caught with the payroll on us.
Watch where I throw it,
we'll pick it up later.
(clattering)
We finally got a break.
They called me down to the jail hospital
to see if I could identify a prisoner
and he turned out to be one of those two
who've been making all the trouble for us.
Well how did they catch him?
Well he and another man
staged a payroll robbery.
The police went after
them and the car crashed.
The other man was killed but her pal
was only banged up a little.
What did you find out about him?
His name's Graber, he's an ex-convict
out on parole from a bank robbery sentence.
Well what about his connection
with the invaders from the moon?
I haven't had a chance to find out yet.
There were too many people
around the jail hospital
so Henderson asked me not
to question him there.
We might be overheard.
But aren't they going to
try to find out something?
Yes.
They're going to move him under guard
to a private sanitarium
where we can question
him without any danger
of the story leaking out
and throwing the whole country into a panic.
When will that be?
Probably this afternoon.
Henderson is going to let me know as soon as
they make arrangements for
having him transferred.
I'd like you to go with me Ted.
Sure.
(light dramatic music)
I got some news about Graber.
A friend of mine's a
trustee in the jail hospital
and he tipped me off they're moving Graber
out in an ambulance this afternoon.
Is there anything we can do about it?
Yeah I got it all figured out.
Now my friend told me which road
the ambulance is taking and I'll...
(light dramatic music)
(tires screeching)
Start walking across country.
Go on!
What about the driver?
I sent him hiking.
You should have slugged him.
As soon as he gets to a phone
he'll have the cops on our trial.
Nah, it's okay.
There's a car parked a few miles
up the road to pick you up.
Okay, let's go.
(dramatic music)
(engine rumbling)
It's about time you got here,
the cops are after you already.
What?
Yeah it's coming over the radio right now.
[Dispatch] Calling all
cars, calling all cars.
The stolen ambulance was last reported
turning onto the east end
of Harrison Canyon Highway.
I told ya you should
have slugged that driver.
[Dispatch] Calling police headquarters,
calling police headquarters.
It's Cody.
[Dispatch] Police headquarters, come in.
[Cody] This is Commando Cody, I picked up
your broadcast and I'm just turning in
to the west end of Harrison Canyon now.
If I meet the ambulance
I'll stop it for you.
[Dispatch] We'll get some
men up there soon as we can.
That's a bad break.
What's he doing out here?
Probably on his way to third degree me.
I'll go back to town with you Sam.
You keep going with the
ambulance until you can ditch it.
If you meet Cody first smash him.
Right!
(engine rumbling)
Do you think we'll meet them on the road?
We got a good chance to.
(suspenseful music)
There it is!
It's gonna crash into us!
(crashing)
(dramatic music)
Do you think we'll meet them on the road?
We've got a good chance to.
(dramatic music)
There it is!
It's gonna crash into us!
[Cody] Bail out!
(crashing)
(light music)
Here's the payroll.
We found it right where it was thrown.
Splendid.
Now we can...
-Retik calling Krog.
Retik calling Krog.
Yes, Your Excellency?
I was just about to call
you to report that we are
about to put our ray gun
into operation again.
I have another mission for you first.
Do you have an atomic bomb strong enough to
start a volcanic eruption
in the Mount Aldo Crater?
Yes but an eruption in that mountainous
area would do very little damage.
On the contrary, it will
do a great deal of damage.
The present atmospheric
conditions on Earth indicate
that the eruption would
cause torrential rains
and the resulting floods should seriously
disrupt transportation and defense measures.
Excellent idea.
We shall carry it out at once.
Very well.
Then start an intensified
campaign with the ray gun.
Earth's defenses must be
completely broken down
before we can risk an
invasion from the moon.
Yes Your Excellency.
You heard the orders,
charter a plane and drop one
of our atomic bombs into the outer crater.
Nature will do the rest.
Okay, when do we do it?
At once.
I will get you the bomb.
(light suspenseful music)
(rumbling) (dramatic music)
Here it goes.
(booming)
If the moon men did start that eruption
they certainly got results.
Well somebody must have started it.
That volcano has been dead for years.
Took quite a blast to get it going again.
An atomic bomb dropped from a plane
would seem to be the only answer.
You know Commando Cody thinks that maybe...
(door clicking)
How'd you make out?
I think we're on the right track.
The second airport I checked had chartered
the plane on the day of the eruption to two
men answering the description
of Graber and his pal.
Then we're right.
They're the ones who bombed the volcano.
Looks like it.
Yes but that doesn't help us catch them.
Couldn't you get a line on them?
The names and addresses
they gave were phony,
but I did get one break.
The airport manager borrowed these matches
from Graber and forgot to give them back.
Al's Cafe.
That might do us some good.
It at least means they've been there
and if we're lucky they
might be regular customers.
So let's go and look the joint over.
Right.
If we hear anything Joan,
we'll give you a call.
Yeah I know the guys you mean.
They come in here pretty often
but I don't know their
names or anything about 'em.
Well, if they show up I wish you'd call me.
Oh, sure.
I sure will, Mr. Cody.
Thanks.
(dramatic music)
(thudding)
(clattering)
(shattering)
(grunting)
Drop it or I'll drill him.
If you or the cops try to follow us
I'll give it to him quick.
They took your pal Mr. Cody.
You gonna call the cops?
I don't dare to.
They'd kill him sure.
(banging) (dramatic music)
(tires screeching)
[Daly] We'll never find him down there.
You're right.
And as soon as he can get to a phone
he'll have the cops on our trail.
The road to Clark Mountain is just up ahead.
We'll hide out there until
Krog can send us another car.
Calling Krog.
[Krog] Come in, Graber.
We just had a run-in with Cody again.
Our car is hot.
We'll have to have another one.
[Krog] Where are you?
We're heading up to Clark Mountain.
We'll stop before we get
to the top and wait there.
Very well I'll have another car out
there as soon as possible.
(dramatic music)
What do you think they'll do to him?
Oh it's hard to tell.
They'll certainly hold him until they...
(phone ringing)
Cody Laboratory.
Ted, where are you!
In a gas station on Highway 17.
I jumped out of the car
and gave them the slip.
Good work.
Now we can go after them.
Where are they heading?
They were going up the Clark Mountain road.
I'll use the rocket
suit and try to find them.
Okay.
Don't worry about me I'll
come right back to town.
Phone the police and
tell the block to highway
on the other side of the mountain.
Right.
Police headquarters.
(dramatic music)
(blasting)
Hey, Daly.
Quit worrying.
Car can't get here for a while yet.
(dramatic music)
Hey, hey it's Cody.
(banging)
(dramatic music)
It's time to get out of here.
Follow me, keep low.
(dramatic music)
When Cody gets here give yourself up.
Try not to get too close to him.
-But look...
-Don't argue,
do what I tell ya.
(suspenseful music)
[Cody] Don't move.
Drop your gun.
Where's Graber?
(thudding)
(dramatic music)
When Cody gets here give yourself up.
Try not to get too close to him.
-But look...
-Don't argue,
do what I tell ya.
Don't move.
Drop your gun.
Where's Graber?
(thudding) (dramatic music)
(whooshing)
I got the flying suit under control just
before I crashed but I'd lost my gun.
When I tried to look for Graber
and his pal they had disappeared.
They'd must have taken
over the hills on foot.
So where are we now?
About back where we started.
Except that we do know that Graber's
been hanging out at Al's Cafe.
They'll probably never show up there again.
But I might find somebody
around there who knows them.
Anyway I'm going to give it a try.
I'll call you later.
Sure I've seen him around
here and talked to him
a few times but I don't
know anything about him.
What'd you talk to him about?
Well I'm a mechanic and
the last time he asked me
to do some work on a truck motor for him
I couldn't handle the
job so yesterday it was,
I told him to try Benson's
over on the south side of town
but I don't know whether they
ever went over there or not.
I'll check up on that.
Do you know Benson's address?
It's on Central between 14th and 15th.
South side of the street.
Good, thanks.
I'll let you know if they ever turn
up here again Mr. Cody.
Good, see you later.
(light spooky music)
Krog calling Retik.
Come in, Krog.
We have the new ray gun ready to mount in
a well camouflaged truck Your Excellency.
And are prepared to renew our campaign.
Good.
What are your first objectives?
Since the authorities here learned of
your planned invasion from the moon,
there have been heavy troop
movements in this area.
We plan to concentrate on
destroying troop trains.
Very well.
Work as fast as possible.
We must have Earth's defenses
completely disorganized
before we start our invasion from the moon.
Yes, Your Excellency.
Is everything ready?
Yes, we can pick up the truck and get going.
Here are the timetables.
The map with the best
points of attack indicated.
Cover as many of them as you can today.
Right.
(light dramatic music)
No, I don't remember anyone
answering that description
but of course we run a
lot of jobs through here
and I don't know all the drivers.
How about these trucks that are in here now?
Well this one and this one are
a couple of my regular customers.
That was a cross-country
job it came in last night
for an ignition check.
I didn't see who the driver was,
the night man took care of it.
Okay if I look it over?
Sure, go ahead.
(rattling)
(clanking)
Get away from that truck.
Hey, what's going on?
Frisk him.
Stay out of this or you'll get hurt.
Now look, I don't want any trouble in here.
(dramatic music) (grunting)
(thudding)
(clattering)
Let's roll.
(engine rumbling)
That truckload of radios was a phony.
That whole back end was a fake door.
I'm sure they're planning
and hiding something inside.
Probably a ray gun.
That's what I'm afraid of.
They'll probably start
blasting again any time now.
I've sent Ted out to the airport to stand
by in a plane with some light bombs.
Soon as we hear of any ray gun attacks
I'll fly out and try to locate that truck
and radio Ted to bomb it.
(phone ringing)
Cody Laboratory.
All right, we'll be right out.
They just blasted a troop train in the
east end of Carson Valley.
Radio Ted to take off and in a plane
at once and fly around out there.
I'll contact him as soon
as I spot the truck.
Right away.
Calling Ted Richards.
(dramatic music)
[Cody] Calling Ted Richards.
Calling Ted Richards.
This is Ted, come in.
[Cody] I've spotted the truck.
It's going along a dirt road just east
of the end of the valley.
I'll be right with you.
[Cody] Okay, I'll keep them
in sight until you show up.
(dramatic music)
Cody's after us again!
We'll stop him, use the rifle.
(banging)
Did you get him?
No, but I scared him off.
So he'll fly back and
tell the cops where we are?
So what?
By the time they get out
here we'll be long gone.
[Cody] Ted, Ted.
This is Ted.
[Cody] You're headed the right direction,
just keep going I'm coming aboard.
Right.
(dramatic music)
What gives?
The truck's just ahead.
Fly over to that dirt road.
Okay.
[Cody] Where are the bombs?
Right there.
Right a little.
That's good, just keep going.
Okay.
(booming)
What was that?
There's a plane up
there, he must of bombed us
and looks like he's coming
back for another try.
I'll stop.
We'll give a blast with our ray gun.
That was pretty close but drop
down a little lower next time.
Okay.
Hey, they've stopped.
Looks like they're aiming a gun at us.
Dive on 'em, quick!
Okay.
(engine rumbling)
Hurry it up, he's diving on us again!
(booming)
Ya missed!
He came too quick.
Turn the truck around, I'll
get another shot at him.
Right!
[Cody] They're getting
set for another shot at us.
Get going.
(booming)
(dramatic music)
Ya missed!
Came too quick.
Turn the truck around, I
can get another shot at him.
Right!
(engine rumbling)
[Cody] They're getting
set for another shot at us.
Get going.
Better bail out.
Okay.
(booming)
(dramatic music)
It's going to be a serious problem
organizing any system of
defense against those ray guns.
It's practically impossible
unless we build ray guns of our own.
We can't do that without lunarium
as the base for the atom reaction.
That's right.
So if it meets with your
approval I'll make another trip
to the moon and try to
get a supply of lunarium.
Do you think you can do it?
I'm not sure but it's worth trying.
Anything is better than sitting here
like tin ducks in a shooting gallery.
I heartily agree and
if you're willing to make
the attempt you can
certainly have permission.
How soon can you start?
Right away.
The rocket ship is all fueled and ready.
Joan, phone Hank and tell me get
the jets warmed up, we leave right away.
I want to get started
before there's any chance
of the news leaking out so Retik won't
be laying for us when we get there.
(light dramatic music)
Well boys, that's it.
Hope this trip is as easy as your last one.
Thanks, it should be.
-Goodbye.
Goodbye, sir.
Hiya, folks, here we go again.
Hello, Hank, all set?
Any time now.
(engine rumbling)
Safety belts fastened?
Fire pilot jets.
(hissing)
Fire main jets.
We're full speed, Hank.
Set a course for the Moon.
Right!
(light dramatic music)
Take over here, will ya, Ted?
We're just about here.
We oughta be down in another two hours.
(hissing)
I can see the city now.
We don't wanna get too close,
so swing west, Hank and
head to that same canyon.
Okay.
We're almost to the canyon now.
Okay, I'll take her down.
All right, set her down.
(dramatic music)
You sure you don't me to go along?
No, not this time.
This is just a scouting trip to try
to find where they keep the lunarium.
[Joan] How do you expect to do that?
Well if I'm lucky I'll
be able to capture one of
the moon men and get some
information out of him.
(light dramatic music)
(buzzing)
(blasting)
(dramatic music)
[Cody] Do you want me
to cut off your air again?
[Moon Man] No, no.
[Cody] Where is the lunarium stored?
[Moon Man] I will tell you.
Think I'll pass?
Sure, you'll pass all right,
if that joker told the truth.
He wasn't any position to lie very well.
Now it's just lucky I picked up
one of the men who guard the lunariam.
If we're gonna get there in time for you
to take his place we better hurry.
(light dramatic music)
It's a little after 9:00.
I'll go right in, you find a place to hide
and watch for me to come out.
[Ted] Okay.
(creaking)
[Moon Man] About time you got here.
[Cody] I was delayed.
(banging)
(creaking)
(buzzing)
You've got it!
[Moon Man] Yes, it's so heavy it's going to
take us a week to lug it back to the ship.
Get out of sight, quick!
(engine rumbling)
(creaking)
Come on.
[Moon Man] Parol number six reporting.
(suspenseful music)
That is all, very well.
(rumbling)
This is patrol number six.
Somebody stole my car,
send another one quickly.
[Cody] How's the fuel pressure?
[Ted] Seems okay.
[Cody] Make all the speed you can.
There he is.
That's right where they're amiss.
That might stop it.
(booming)
[Ted] What was that?
[Cody] A ray gun blast.
See what's behind us.
(dramatic music)
[Ted] There's another car chasing us.
We'd better use our gun.
[Cody] We'll have to turn around to do it.
There's a bunch of rocks ahead
that will give us some shelter.
We'll wait till we get there.
(suspenseful music)
[Ted] It's heading for some rocks,
we'll have to stop it.
(booming)
That's our feed pressure line, we're stuck.
[Ted] I'll say we are.
[Cody] Pressure's down to nothing.
[Ted] I can fix this if I have time.
Fly out and try to stop
them with your grenades.
[Cody] Okay.
[Moon Man] They stopped behind a rock,
but I think I can blast them.
(blasting)
(booming)
(air hissing) (dramatic music)
(dramatic music)
[Ted] There's a bunch of rocks ahead
that will give us some shelter.
[Moon Man] He's heading for some rocks,
we'll have to stop him.
(booming)
(clattering)
[Ted] That's our feed
pressure line, we're stuck.
[Cody] I'll say we are.
[Ted] Pressure's down to nothing.
I could fix this if I have time.
Fly out and try to stop
them with your grenades.
[Cody] Okay.
[Moon Man] He stopped behind a rock.
But I think I can blast him.
(dramatic music)
(booming)
(rattling)
-What was that?
(air hissing)
We're stuck!
-So is the other car.
[Moon Man] Let's go after
him with our ray pistols.
[Cody] Feel better?
[Ted] Yes.
Did you stop them?
[Cody] For a little while,
but I don't know for how long.
[Ted] You better go out
and see what's happening
while I try to fix that feed pressure line.
[Cody] Okay.
(dramatic music)
(booming)
[Ted] Hey!
(rumbling)
Get Hank and put this aboard.
Get set for a takeoff as fast as you can.
I'll ditch this car.
[Cody] Right.
[Hank] Okay we're ready.
Right.
[Moon Man] Aren't you going
to let me go before you leave?
No we're taking you
with us and you better go
back to your quarters until we get started.
Get going!
Safety belts fastened?
Fire pilot jets.
(roaring)
Fire main jets.
(hissing)
Well, we're on our way.
And am I glad.
I'll go get us some coffee.
(thudding)
(dramatic music)
(grunting)
(air hissing)
(clattering)
(banging)
What'll they do with him Hank?
It's just like a burial at sea, Joan.
Only his body will float
around in space forever.
Everything okay, Hank?
She's under control now.
Good.
Make a 180 degree turn and head for home.
Okay!
(dramatic music)
(light music)
Retik calling Krog.
This is Krog, Your Excellency.
[Retik] The rocket ship
from Earth has been here again
and has escaped with a supply of lunarium.
That's serious, now they
can build their own ray guns
and prevent your invasion from the moon.
Of course.
So their ship must not be allowed to land.
Calculate the time of their arrival
and have your ray gun set
up ready to blast them.
This time you must not fail.
Your own life and the future
of our people are at stake.
I understand, Your Excellency.
You heard the orders, there
must be no bumbling this time.
I will draw up a detailed
plan of operations.
(dramatic music)
There we are.
We ought to be able to
pick up the good ol' Earth
on a scanning screen pretty quick.
Here it comes, right when Krog figured.
Wait'll it turns in for a landing.
Okay.
All right, Hank, make your 180 degree turn.
(blasting)
Going in for a landing.
Any time now.
(booming)
That was a ray gun blast.
Take her up again, quick!
Quite too soon, it wasn't close enough.
Keep going up, we've
got to stay out of range.
Okay, but then what?
We're almost out of fuel.
Gotta set her down sometime.
It's probably Graber and Daly
on a truck with a ray gun.
I'll try to stop them!
Still climbing slow,
but it's way out of range.
Well, they'll have to come down some time.
Yeah but we're gonna have trouble first.
Here comes Cody in his flying suit.
Get him in your sights and blast him
when he gets close enough.
(dramatic music)
If I wait for him to get any closer,
he'll be right over us.
Then take a shot at him!
(booming) (dramatic music)
Well this is it, folks, we've gotta turn back
and land before we're clear outta fuel.
Rocket's coming in again.
Get set for it.
This time, wait'll it gets
so close you can't miss.
(rustling)
(suspenseful music)
(banging)
Through the ray gun at him!
(booming)
Forget him, get the rocket.
It's almost down.
Now what?
We gotta get Cody first, give it a blast.
I can't get at him behind that rock.
Then hit the cliff above
him and bring it down on him.
(booming)
(rumbling)
(dramatic music)
(dramatic music) (banging)
Forget him, get the rocket.
It's almost down.
(dramatic music) (banging)
(banging)
Now what?
We gotta get Cody first, give him a blast.
I can't get at him behind that rock.
Then hit the cliff above
him and bring it down on him.
(booming) (rumbling)
Did that get him?
Can't tell.
But we missed the rocket,
it's already landed on the
other side of the hill.
Maybe we can blast them before
they get a chance to unload.
No, there'll be too many guards there,
we might lose the ray gun.
We'd better pull outta here.
(dramatic music)
(spooky music)
This is serious.
And Cody did escape,
I heard the announcement over the radio.
I must report to the moon.
Krog calling Retik.
Come in, Krog.
I have very bad news, Your Excellency.
Commando Cody has upset our plans
for destroying the rocket ship
and the lunarium has been landed.
This is intolerable.
If the Earth people use that
lunarium to build ray guns
they will be able to repel our invasion.
[Krog] I realize that, but I did my best.
Your best is not good enough!
I'm going to fly down to Earth at once
and take charge of operations myself.
I will welcome your help.
Apparently you need it.
In the meantime, have your
men go after Commando Cody
and any other key personnel they can reach.
We must delay the completion
of any ray guns on Earth
until my invasion fleet is ready.
Yes, Your Excellency.
(dramatic music)
Cody and his assistants must be destroyed.
The lunarium arrived safely
at the government atomic laboratory
and they've already started converting
it into a compound suitable
for use in the ray gun.
How long will that take?
Some time, I'm afraid.
The element's entirely
new to our scientists,
and they'll have to build
considerable equipment to handle it.
Well I hope they can get it ready
before the moon men attack.
Do you have any idea when
the invasion may be expected?
No.
The moon ruler told me
himself he was planning
the attack, but he didn't say when.
The time element is vital.
Let's go over in detail what happened
on your trip to the moon and perhaps
we can find some clue to
when they plan to strike.
All right.
Well, our passage through
space was uneventful.
The rocket ship functioned perfectly.
When we reached the moon,
I decided to go on a scouting trip.
(light suspenseful music)
(door creaking)
Welcome, Commando Cody.
I am Retik, ruler of the moon.
Apparently you were expecting me.
Of course.
For many years our radio
has kept us informed
of the events on Earth, and my men there
have advised me of your every move.
[Cody] I see you have adopted our language.
Yes.
All our people are required to speak English
so we can operate more
efficiently in your country.
Do you mind telling me why your men
are carrying out that campaign
of destruction on Earth?
Not at all.
They are merely softening up your defenses
for our impending invasion.
[Cody] Why do you want to invade the earth?
'Cause the atmosphere on the Moon
has become so thin and dry it is impossible
for us to raise food except
in pressurized greenhouses.
And none of us can move
outside without helmets.
So we are planning a mass
migration to your world.
You'll find that conquering
the Earth isn't so simple.
Ah, but it will be.
Because of our atomic weapons.
On the Moon we have an element, lunarium,
which is far superior to uranium
as a base for atomic reactions.
And we can completely control
the force of these reactions,
enabling us to build atomic weapons ranging
from huge canon to these small ray pistols.
It's very considerate of you
to give me all this information.
You deserve some reward
for your long journey,
but unfortunately I cannot permit
you to return to Earth with it.
Maybe I have something to say about that.
(whirring)
So much for the
effectiveness of your weapons.
Now I will demonstrate one of ours.
(dramatic music)
(booming)
Seize him!
(thudding)
(clattering)
(booming)
We decided we would need a ray gun
if we were to attack the city.
So the next day, Ted and
I went back and turned
nitrous oxide into their ventilating system.
When Retik and his guard became unconscious,
Ted waited while I went
in and got a ray gun.
But before we could... (dramatic music)
They're still after us.
Let's go.
(rumbling)
[Ted] That looks like a
cave, let's get in there.
[Moon Man] We can't follow them in there.
Set the ray gun at constant heat.
We'll melt the cliff and bury them alive.
[Moon Man] Right.
(dramatic music)
[Ted] What's that?
[Cody] They've turned the ray gun
to the side of the cave
and there's no way to run.
Let's get back as far as we can.
Never mind the gun!
(rumbling)
[Ted] Maybe we can get out along that side.
[Cody] But what about that tank?
[Ted] We may be able to take care of it.
Let's try this way.
I hated to lose that ray gun,
but it would only have
been good for a few shots
without another charge of lunarium.
And now that we have a lunarium,
we can build our own ray guns and pistols.
Yes.
We brought back one of their ray pistols.
[Henderson] Looks fairly simple.
[Cody] Yes, would you
like me to take it apart
to show you how it works?
[Henderson] Please.
(dramatic music)
There's the intake for
the air conditioning system.
Put the hose in and turn the gas on.
(whirring)
Let's find a spot where we can watch
the window in case anyone tries to get out.
We must start manufacturing
these weapons at once.
Wouldn't it be better to save the lunarium
for bigger guns?
They're what we'll need to stop
an invasion by rocket ships.
Excuse me, but isn't getting
awfully stuffy in here?
I'll open a window.
(dramatic music)
(banging) (glass shattering)
You better get her out
of here, Mr. Henderson.
(thudding)
It won't open!
(dramatic music)
(light dramatic music)
(hissing)
(banging)
You better get her out
of here, Mr. Henderson.
(rattling)
This won't open!
(thudding)
(alarm ringing)
We'd better get outta
here, that'll bring the cops.
We can't yet.
(clanking)
(sniffing)
Well, I guess that finished him.
Let's get outta here.
I'm all right now.
He seems to be coming around all right.
Somebody took a shot at me from outside.
I'm going to go look for them.
You'd better stay here with him.
(light dramatic music)
(banging)
It's Graber and Daly.
Come on!
-I'll drive.
-Okay.
[Henderson] What's the matter?
Somebody stole my car,
I've gotta get to a phone to report it.
[Graber] There's a car
following us, keep rolling.
(banging)
We'll have to get closer.
[Dispatch] Calling all
cars, calling all cars.
A black sedan has been stolen from
in front of Cody Laboratory.
Last seen going north, get after it.
Cody must've taken the cop's car.
I hope they take after him instead of us.
(engines rumbling)
We've got some help,
there's some motor cops right behind us.
What if the cops are on our side?
All we have to do is stay
ahead of Cody a little longer.
(gun banging)
I'm out of shells.
Try to get alongside and
I'll use that gas grenade.
He's catching up with us.
(thudding)
Try again, that threw me off balance.
(banging)
(coughing)
(tires screeching)
[Joan] I can't see a thing!
Something's wrong with their car.
Slow down.
(crashing)
Get out with your hands up.
[Officer] We'll handle this.
Wait a minute, officer.
I'm Commando Cody.
These men tried to murder
us in my laboratory.
Yeah, well all I know is
that you stole the police car,
so I'm taking the whole bunch a
you down to the station.
Come on, get in the car.
All of you.
Certainly, officer.
That's a good idea.
You must've done some fast
talking to get out of that.
No, as soon as I convinced them who I was
everything was all right.
Did you find out anything
from Graber and Daly?
Not a thing.
They denied they ever used the ray gun
or that they have anything to do
with the planned invasion form the moon.
But you can testify that you've seen
them using the ray gun.
I could but I'm not going to.
What?
My testimony could convict them,
but what good would it do?
They're just hired thugs.
And whoever is boss of
this show could easily
hire someone else to operate the ray guns.
But it's ridiculous to
turn those murderers loose.
I know it looks that way,
but it's the only way to
locate their headquarters
and perhaps smash the whole gang.
How do you figure that?
Well, I've instructed
the police to release them
and trail them until they leave town.
Then they'll radio me and I'll take over.
(light dramatic music)
Still can't figure out how
we got out of that so easy.
Yeah.
Did seem kind of phony.
There's a car back there
and it might be tailing us.
Do we run for it?
Not yet.
Take it easy till we
make sure he's after us.
[Dispatch] Calling Commando Cody.
Calling Commando Cody.
This is Commando Cody, come in.
[Dispatch] Your men are headed out of town
on Highway number 19.
They are driving at a
moderate rate of speed.
They should pass the city
limits in about five minutes.
I'll get out there right away.
Well, I hope it works.
Good luck.
You're sure you won't need me?
No, Ted, but thanks anyway.
(blasting)
(dramatic music)
That car turned off so I
guess it wasn't following us.
Head for the cave.
Right.
I can't understand why
they let you off so easy,
but it's very fortunate
you came back when you did.
Retik has arrived.
He came down in his personal rocket ship.
He landed it in the cave in the east side
of the old Mount Henry mine.
I just spoke to him by radio.
He wants us to arrange for four more trucks
and eight men to operate the
ray guns he brought with him.
[Graber] Okay, we'll go to town and get 'em.
[Cody] Get those hands higher.
(dramatic music)
(clattering)
(grunting)
(thudding)
(crashing)
(sizzling) (screaming)
(gun banging)
(sizzling)
(dramatic music)
(spooky music)
(dramatic music) (clattering)
(thudding)
(grunting)
(sizzling) (screaming)
(gun banging)
(sizzling)
They're both finished.
[Daly] So what do we do now?
This is Retik, ruler of the Moon.
You will carry out Krog's orders.
Get the men and the trucks necessary
to operate my ray guns and
bring them here at once!
(dramatic instrumental music)
And there was enough metal in my flying suit
to partially ground the current
so I was only knocked out,
but the other man was killed instantly.
From what you've told us,
he must've been the leader
of the Moon forces here.
I think so.
But now that Retik is on
Earth, he'll take command.
And if Graber and Daly
carry out their orders,
he'll soon have a strong
force of men and ray guns.
Then we must capture him
before he can get organized.
If he has ray guns there, it won't be easy.
No, but at least we can get the ray gun
in Krog's cave and use it ourselves.
I'll arrange to have it picked up at once.
If you will have it mounted on a truck
it can be taken directly
from there to the mine.
Ted and I will go out and scout around
so we can move in on them as
soon as the ray gun gets there.
I'll get it to you as quickly as possible.
Yes, sir.
Do you know exactly where
the Mount Henry mine is?
Yes, it's an old abandoned one.
It has two entrances and a...
(phone ringing)
Cody Laboratory.
Yes, he's here.
Hello?
This is the bartender
at Al's Cafe, Mr. Cody.
[Cody] Yes?
Those two men you asked me
to watch for just came in.
They're talking to some other fellas.
Looks like they're tryin' to work up a deal.
We'll be right down.
Graber and Daly are at Al's Cafe.
We have time to pick them up and still get
to the mine before the truck.
That's their car, all right.
(dramatic music)
Get to your feet.
Search him.
(thudding) (dramatic music)
(grunting)
(clattering)
(crashing)
(thudding)
Come on, now.
(suspenseful music)
They're after us, keep rolling!
(gun banging)
(tires screeching)
(horn honking)
(crashing) (booming)
No chance of getting them out of that.
No.
Let's go after Retik.
Everything all right?
Seems to be.
We were delayed getting here
and I don't know what the
set up is in the mine.
So you stay here with the gun
while we do some scouting.
Yes, sir.
Should be here by now.
Go out to the mine entrance
and see if there's any sign of them.
Yes sir.
Let's take a look inside.
(suspenseful music) (gun banging)
(thudding)
You take that tunnel, I'll take this one!
(blasting)
He's getting away in his
rocket, let's get to the truck.
Get the gun ready, quick!
(booming)
Now that Retik's dead, we feel sure there's
no immediate danger of any
enemy invasion from the moon.
And we'll have time to
build an adequate defense.
Will you want us to make another trip to
the moon to see what's going on?
I don't think so now that
the moon men's attack has failed.
We can make the whole story public
and the military
authorities can take charge.
But we will need more of
your rocket ships, Commando,
so I suggest you make plans for going
into their manufacture on a large scale.
Before we get started on
ships using regular rocket fuel,
let's do some experimenting
with atomic power from lunarium.
That might be pretty hard to control.
No, I've got it all figured out.
Stand back, please.
Look, by setting the controls
on this model rocket,
I can make it slowly circle
the room and come right back.
Watch.
Here we go!
(hissing)
(shattering)
I thought you said it
was going to slowly circle
the room and come back.
At least it did come back.
(laughing)
(light instrumental music)